Rafael Iván Corrales de Haro

 • Mexico
 ■ rafa.deharo@outlook.com
 □ 7221091822
 ■ in/rafadeharo

SUMMARY

Results-driven professional with experience in data analysis, customer experience and an internship in project management. I have developed a strong track record in driving operational efficiency, improving customer satisfaction visibility, and delivering value to stakeholders.

SKILLS

Data Analysis: Tableau (Advanced), PowerBI (Basic), SQL (Intermediate).

Languages: Spanish (Native), English (Advanced), German (Basic).

EDUCATION

Industrial and Systems Engineering

Tecnológico de Monterrey · Toluca, México · 2019 · 93

EXPERIENCE

Performance Analyst

Kushki

March 2022 - Present, Mexico City

- Developed and implemented follow-up dashboards and reports to track the progress of the product development team, reducing inquiry time by up to 50%. These dashboards enabled the team to make data-driven decisions and improve overall efficiency.
- Initiated and executed comprehensive Customer Experience and Net Promoter Score (NPS) surveys for the top merchants of Kushki to measure satisfaction levels, resulting in a new level of visibility regarding the customer experience of Kushki. These surveys enabled the company to identify areas for improvement and develop targeted strategies to improve customer satisfaction.
- Created and designed Transactional dashboards to provide key stakeholders with real-time visibility of transactional information, including transaction volume, total processed value, and acceptance rates.

Senior Performance Analyst

Kavak

October 2020 - February 2022, Mexico City

- Designed, developed and implemented a comprehensive set of post-sale Key Performance Indicators (KPIs), dashboards and reports for the main operations stakeholders. These reports provided valuable insights and decision-making tools that helped the team to monitor performance, identify issues and make data-driven decisions.
- Developed and managed tools and data visibility systems that enabled continuous monitoring of customer experience metrics, including Net Promoter Score (NPS), Customer Satisfaction (CSAT), and other relevant indicators. By providing real-time access to this data, stakeholders were able to identify trends, respond quickly to customer feedback, and take proactive steps to improve customer satisfaction.
- Utilized data management techniques and created SQL queries to facilitate the usage of data for internal consumption. By developing user-friendly dashboards and data visualization tools, data was made accessible and easy to understand, empowering stakeholders to make informed decisions and act with confidence.

Engine Project Management Trainee

September 2019 - July 2020, Toluca

- Supported Engine Project Management team by tracking and following up on required documentation for engine projects, ensuring compliance with regulatory requirements and project deadlines.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Oversaw large Excel data documents by formatting, cleaning up, and organizing information for main stakeholders of the engine project management team.}$
- \cdot Communicated with international managers to obtain key information necessary for the successful management and follow-up of diverse engine projects. This involved collaborating with multicultural teams to ensure clear and effective communication.
- Conducted regular follow-up on critical autoparts for diverse engines to ensure timely and effective project development. This involved coordinating and tracking alongside the inventory team and identifying potential issues before they impacted project timelines or quality.

COURSEWORK

Python Data Structures

University of Michigan (Coursera) • 2023 • Python

Business Intelligence Fundation

CertiProf · 2023 · Business Intelligence

Foundations: Data, Data, Everywhere Google (Coursera) · 2023 · Data Analysis

Foundations of Project Management

Google (Coursera) · 2022 · Project Management

Agile with Atlassian Jira Atlassian University (Coursera) · 2022 · Agile

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

University of Michigan (Coursera) · 2022 · Python

SQL For Data Science

UC Davis (Coursera) · 2022 · SQL

Design Principles for Effective Dashboard Desgin

Udemy · 2022 · Dashboard Design

PROJECTS

Spanish Tutoring

Fort Worth Sister Cities • June 2018 - July 2018

- · Planned, developed and taught Spanish courses for American students (elementary school level) at Fort Worth, Texas.
- · Implemented teaching methods to develop students' vocabulary, grammar, writing and oral communication Spanish skills.
- · Developed creative activities to engage with young students during the duration of the summer camp.